<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Mårten Söderblom Saarela</title>
    <link>https://martensoderblomsaarela.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Mårten Söderblom Saarela</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 04 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://martensoderblomsaarela.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Reviews of The Early Modern Travels of Manchu</title>
      <link>https://martensoderblomsaarela.github.io/blog/reviewsofearlymoderntravelsofmanchu/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://martensoderblomsaarela.github.io/blog/reviewsofearlymoderntravelsofmanchu/</guid>
      <description>A list of reviews of The Early Modern Travels of Manchu: A Script and Its Study in East Asia and Europe (Philadelphia: University of Pennsylvania Press, 2020):
 Peter Kornicki in [History of Humanities] 6.1 (2021): 353&amp;ndash;355](https://doi.org/10.1086/713278).
David Porter in the Bulletin of the School of Oriental and African Studies 84.1 (2021): 191-193.
Lars Laamann in the Journal of Jesuit Studies 8.1 (2000): 143-146.
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Errata</title>
      <link>https://martensoderblomsaarela.github.io/blog/errata/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://martensoderblomsaarela.github.io/blog/errata/</guid>
      <description>The Early Modern Travels of Manchu: A Script and Its Study in East Asia and Europe (Philadelphia: University of Pennsylvania Press, 2020): pp. 22-24: The translations from the Jinshi 金史 (History of the Jin) and Yuanshi 元史 (History of the Yuan) contain mistakes. Corrected versions will hopefully appear in a different publication in 2021 or 2022 (update to follow). p. 133: &amp;ldquo;1780s&amp;rdquo; should read &amp;ldquo;1680s.&amp;rdquo; p. 168: &amp;ldquo;It</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Encyclopedia entry on the Manchu language</title>
      <link>https://martensoderblomsaarela.github.io/blog/manchulanguageore/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://martensoderblomsaarela.github.io/blog/manchulanguageore/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;Manchu Language,&amp;rdquo; Oxford Research Encyclopedia of Asian History March 25, 2021.
Abstract:
 The Manchu language was the language of state in the Qing empire, which ruled China and large parts of Inner Asia from 1644 to 1911. For much of its history, it was used by communities in which Chinese was also spoken and written, but Manchu is a Tungusic language that is unrelated to Chinese. Its implementation in China and maintenance as the administrative language of core elements of the Qing imperial bureaucracy prompted the development of a Manchu education system and a tradition of bilingual Manchu-Chinese language pedagogy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Article on Linguistic Compartmentalization and the Palace Memorial System</title>
      <link>https://martensoderblomsaarela.github.io/blog/linguisticcompartmentalization/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://martensoderblomsaarela.github.io/blog/linguisticcompartmentalization/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;Linguistic Compartmentalization and the Palace Memorial System in the Eighteenth Century,&amp;rdquo; Late Imperial China 41.2 (2020): 131–179.
The article looks at the Qing dynastic language of Manchu as an issue of governance. It examines instances in which the choice of language rose to the level of discussion in two related genres of official documents that emerged in the eighteenth century: palace memorials and court letters. I argue here that the coexistence of the two written languages of Manchu and Chinese within the government, a fait accompli after 1644, posed a constant problem for official communications.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Cultural and Political History of Spoken Chinese in the Late Imperial Period</title>
      <link>https://martensoderblomsaarela.github.io/blog/historyofmandarin/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://martensoderblomsaarela.github.io/blog/historyofmandarin/</guid>
      <description>This ongoing research project was previously titled &amp;ldquo;A Cultural and Political History of Language in Qing China,&amp;rdquo; but (as of September 2020) I think that its focus on spoken Chinese in particular deserved to be highlighted in the title. In this project, I&amp;rsquo;m trying to figure out how a form of Mandarin Chinese based on the Beijing dialect came to be seen as the language of the government and of the political elite.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Article on Public Inscriptions and Manchu Language Reform</title>
      <link>https://martensoderblomsaarela.github.io/blog/publicinscriptionsandlanguagereform/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://martensoderblomsaarela.github.io/blog/publicinscriptionsandlanguagereform/</guid>
      <description>An article was just published:
&amp;ldquo;Public Inscriptions and Manchu Language Reform in the Early Qianlong Reign (1740s&amp;ndash;60s),&amp;rdquo; Saksaha 16 (2019&amp;ndash;2020): 31&amp;ndash;53.
Abstract
Official signs and steles in the Qing empire were often at least bilingual, with Manchu and Chinese either side by side or on opposite sides. New institutions and renovated buildings necessitated new Manchu words and turns of phrase for the accompanying inscriptions. Under the Qianlong emperor, the text that should go on plaques and steles was carefully scrutinized, especially regarding the use of Manchu vocabulary.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book on the Transnational History of Manchu Studies</title>
      <link>https://martensoderblomsaarela.github.io/blog/earlymoderntravelsofmanchu/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://martensoderblomsaarela.github.io/blog/earlymoderntravelsofmanchu/</guid>
      <description>The Early Modern Travels of Manchu: A Script and Its Study in East Asia and Europe (Philadelphia: University of Pennsylvania Press, 2020) has been published. Right now (March 2020), at least, the promo code PP20 should give you a 20% discount when purchasing the book through the publisher&amp;rsquo;s website.
Here is the description of the book from the University of Pennsylvania Press website:
 Manchu was a language first written down as part of the Qing state-building project in Northeast Asia in the early seventeenth century.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter on Banihûn&#39;s and Pu-gong&#39;s Manchu–Chinese Literary Ocean (1821)</title>
      <link>https://martensoderblomsaarela.github.io/blog/lexicographyoftheentrenchedempire/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://martensoderblomsaarela.github.io/blog/lexicographyoftheentrenchedempire/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;Lexicography of the Entrenched Empire: Banihûn’s and Pu-gong&amp;rsquo;s Manchu–Chinese Literary Ocean (1821),&amp;rdquo; in The Whole World in a Book: Dictionaries in the Nineteenth Century, edited by Sarah Ogilvie and Gabriella Safran, 218&amp;ndash;35 (Oxford: Oxford University Press, 2020). The chapter focuses on a dictionary published by members of the bilingual</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter on the Lexicography of the Languages of the Chinese Periphery</title>
      <link>https://martensoderblomsaarela.github.io/blog/lexicographylanguageschineseperiphery/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://martensoderblomsaarela.github.io/blog/lexicographylanguageschineseperiphery/</guid>
      <description>A book chapter recently came out:
&amp;ldquo;The Chinese Periphery to c. 1800,&amp;rdquo; in The Cambridge World History of Lexicography, edited by John Considine, 202&amp;ndash;22 (Cambridge: Cambridge University Press, 2019).
It discusses the lexicographies of eastern Inner Asia, Japan, and Korea that were directly influenced by the Chinese tradition. The first section talks about lexicography in the Inner Asian empires in the early second millennium AD, with a focus on the lexicography of the Tangut and Mongols in North China.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>